Guide to the Robert A. Caro Archive [DATE]–2021 MS 3203
New-York Historical Society
- Series XI. Scrapbooks, 1952-2021 (bulk, 1974-2020)
  - Scrapbook [27], "RAC-4", 2012-2013 (Box [XI-21])
    [09] "By the Book: Madeleine Albright," New York Times Book Review, April 29, 2012.
    [10-11] Michiko Kakutani, "A Nation's Best and Worst, Forged in a Crucible," New York Times, April 30, 2012.
    [12] "What Robert Caro's LBJ biography 'The Passage of Power' could teach Obama and Romney," Yahoo! News (news.yahoo.com), May 1, 2012.
    [13] Michael Schaub, "'Power': Robert Caro's Life of Johnson Hits the '60s," www.npr.org, May 2, 2012.
    [14] George F. Will, "Robert Caro provides more insight into the Johnson years and liberalism," www.westhawaiitoday.com, April 29, 2012.
    [15] "Harry Potter for history fans: Robert Caro is back with next Lyndon Johnson volume," Washington Post (www.washingtonpost.com), April 30, 2012.
    [16] "Robert Caro: GOP Abuse of Filibuster 'Unconscionable'," taken from Huffington Post, April 30, 2012, www.realjock.com.
    [17a] "Robert Caro's History and Biography Picks," www.barnesandnoble.com, May 5, 2012.
    [17b] "Google alert – robert caro," May 1, 2012.
    [18-19] Michael Schaub, "'Power': Robert Caro's Life of Johnson Hits the '60s," www.npr.org, May 2, 2012.
    [20] Darius Dixon, "Robert Caro: Credit LBJ for Obama," Politico (dyn.politico.com), May 3, 2012.
    [21] Dylan Stableford, "Bill Clinton writes glowing review of Robert Caro's LBJ book for New York Times," abcnews.go.com, May 3, 2012.
    [22] Darius Dixon, "Robert Caro: Credit LBJ for Obama," Politico (dyn.politico.com), May 3, 2012.
    [23-25] Photos of Caro, Mayor Michael Bloomberg, and others at inaugural "NYC Literary Honors," Gracie Mansion, April 26, 2012.
    [24] "Passage of Power" publicity tour schedules, dated April 25, April 30, and May 7, 2012.
    [25] Note from "Sid" on "Poets & Writers" stationery, April 27, 2012, enclosing Ron Rosenbaum, "The Conscience of the King," profile of Caro in Smithsonian, May 2012.
    [26] "That day that changed everything. Robert Caro's masterpiece of biography follows Lyndon Johnson to Dallas—and the White House," The Economist, May 5, 2012.
    [27] John Leland, "Rising Early, [with] a New Sentence in Mind. Sunday Routine | Robert A. Caro," New York Times, May 6, 2012 [5 copies, plus website printout].
    [28] Letter from Sol Tane, May 4, 2012.
    [29] Chris Jones, "The Big Book," Esquire, May 2012.
    [30] Bill Clinton, "Seat of Power," New York Times Book Review, May 6, 2012.
    [31] Charles McGrath, "Robert Caro Is a Dinosaur. And thank God for that," New York Times Magazine, April 15, 2012.
    [32a] "Google alert – robert caro," May 5, 2012.
    [32b] First day cover, "Inauguration of Lyndon B. Johnson, 36th President of the United States," postmarked Washington, D.C., Inauguration Day, January 20, 1965.
    [33a] Note from "Bob," May 2, 2012.
    [33b] Email from Steve Schlesinger, May 4, 2012.
    [33c] Email from Paul Bogaards, May 4, 2012.
    [34] Email from Katherine Hourigan, May 11, 2012.
    [35a] Copy of a Horace Mann class photo (Caro in bottom row) from a school publication.
    [35b] Empty mailing envelope with pencil notations.
    [36a] "Google alert – robert caro," May 19, 2012.
    [36b] "Nicholas Katzenbach dies at age 90, was key aide in Kennedy and Johnson administrations," www.washingtonpost.com, May 10, 2012.
    [36c] Ticket and stub for "Politics & Prose and Politico present Robert Caro, The Passage of Power... Sidwell Friends School," talk / Q&A / signing, Washington, D.C., May 9, 2012.
    [37] Belinda Luscombe, "10 Questions. Lyndon B. Johnson biographer Robert Caro talks about power and why so few Presidents get much done," TIME, May 21, 2012.
    [38] Jill Abramson, "The Elusive President," New York Times Book Review, October 27, 2013.
    [39] "Best Sellers," www.nytimes.com, May 20, 2012.
    [40-41] Wendy Smith, "Book review: 'The Passage of Power: The Years of Lyndon Johnson' by Robert Caro," latimes.com, May 6, 2012.
    [42] John Leland, "Rising Early, With a New Sentence in Mind. Sunday Routine | Robert A. Caro," www.nytimes.com, May 4, 2012.
    [43] Michelle Dean, "Is Optimism About the Future of 'Serious' Publishing Possible?," therumpus.net, May 12, 2012.
    [44] "Trending NOW," nowwithalex.msnbc.msn.com, May 14, 2012.
    [45] "Our Views: Vice presidents must be ready," theadvocate.com, May 14, 2012.
    [46] "Google alert – robert caro," May 14, 2012.
    [47] Jake Chessum photographs (7) of Robert Caro in his office, posed with LBJ volumes, with a letter from the photographer, May 7, 2012.
    [48] "Best Sellers," www.nytimes.com, May 13, 2012.
    [49] Richard Lambert, "Tragedy and triumph. A magisterial biography charts LBJ's progress through the Kennedy years," Financial Times, May 19-20, 2012.
    [50] Photographs of Caro in his office with Horace Mann students from Barry Bienstock's history seminar, April 16, 2012 (see also Scrapbook [28], pages 24-27).
    [52] James M. Perry, "'The Passage of Power': When LBJ Got His Groove Back," Pittsburgh Post-Gazette, April 29, 2012.
    [53] "Best Sellers," New York Times Book Review, May 20, 2012.
    [54] Letter from Thomas J. Putnam, director, John F. Kennedy Presidential Library and Museum, May 18, 2012.
    [55a] "Passage of Power" publicity tour schedules, dated May 11 and 14, 2012.
    [55b] Email from Joel Conarroe, May 19, 2012.
    [56] Garry Wills, "America's Nastiest Blood Feud," The New York Review, May 24, 2012.
    [57] Advertisement for "Passage of Power," New York Times Book Review, May 19, 2013.
    [58] "Best Sellers," New York Times Book Review, May 20, 2012.
  - Scrapbook [28], "RAC-5", 2011-2013 (Box [XI-22])
    Cover embossed "RAC-5." Contains various topics, but largely reviews and publicity of The Years of Lyndon Johnson: The Passage of Power.
    [01] "Vartan Gregorian cordially invites you to a reception to celebrate the publication of Robert Caro's 'The Years of Lyndon Johnson: The Passage of Power'," June 5, 2012.
    [02] "Best Sellers," New York Times Book Review, May 20, 2012.
    [03a] Program for Caro's talk for the New York Society Library / WNET Thirteen, December 5, 2012.
    [03b] Invitation from William P. Kelly, president, Graduate Center, City University of New York, to a cocktail reception and dinner in honor of Caro, May 30, 2012.
    [04-06] Photographs of Robert and Ina Caro at the inaugural NYC Literary Honors, Gracie Mansion, April 26, 2012.
    [07-08] "Best Sellers," New York Times Book Review, May 27, 2012.
    [09-10] Bill Clinton, "Seat of Power," New York Times Book Review, May 6, 2012.
    [11] "Letters" [reactions to Bill Clinton's review of "Passage of Power"], New York Times Book Review, May 20, 2012.
    [12-13] Two-page advertisement for "Passage of Power," New York Times Book Review, May 20, 2012.
    [14] Joe Nocera, "This Story Isn't Over Yet. As a young man, Robert A. Caro was a newspaper reporter" www.nytimes.com, May 7, 2012.
    [15a] Bob Nardini, review of "Passage of Power," Library Journal, May 1, 2012.
    [15b] Robert Caro's visitor badge to 1745 Broadway, June 4, 2012.
    [16-17] Patrick Beach, "LBJ biographer nearing end of story," Austin American-Statesman, May 27, 2012.
    [18-19] Michiko Kakutani, "A Nation's Best and Worst, Forged in a Crucible," New York Times, April 30, 2012.
    [20-21] Patrick Beach, "LBJ biographer nearing end of story," Austin American-Statesman, May 27, 2012.
    [22] Remarks of William P. "Bill" Kelly, president, Graduate Center, City University of New York, introducing Caro at a reception in his honor, May 30, 2012.
    [23] Letter from William P. "Bill" Kelly, president, Graduate Center, City University of New York, June 6, 2012.
    [24-27] Tear sheets from Horace Mann Magazine, vol. 8, no. 1 (Spring 2012); article detailing visit of Barry Bienstock's history seminar students to Caro's office on April 16, 2012. (See also Scrapbook [27], page 50.)
    [28-29] Photos of Robert and Ina Caro and other attendees of an event, likely Vartan Gregorian's reception to celebrate the publication of "Passage of Power," June 5, 2012.
    [30] Photographs of Caro at an event, apparently from an earlier period than the date range of this scrapbook (2012-2013).
    [31] Ronald Brownstein, "The President as Pugilist. Robert Caro's latest volume depicts Lyndon Johnson on the attack—and shows why his methods aren't replicable today," Democracy: A Journal of Ideas, no. 26 (Fall 2012).
    [32-33] Program, "A Meeting of Giants," fourth annual benefit gala, The Norman Mailer Center and the Norman Mailer Writers Colony, Tina Brown, Honorary Chair, October 4, 2012.
    [34] Email from Tina Brown, forwarding her remarks awarding Caro the Norman Mailer distinguished literary biography prize at "A Meeting of Giants Gala," October 5, 2012.
    [35] Email from Anna Schnur-Fishman, Lynn McCary Events, regarding "Norman Mailer Center Gala," September 28, 2012.
    [36] "Caro, Shadid among National Book Award finalists," www.cbsnews.com, October 19, 2012.
    [37] Leon Levy Center for Biography Annual Report, 2011-2012 (incomplete).
    [38] Lily Rothman, "National Book Awards: Junot Diaz, Dave Eggers, Robert Caro Among Finalists," entertainment.time.com, October 10, 2012.
    [39a] The Century Association, The Century Bulletin, October 2012, listing a literary evening with Caro on October 9.
    [39b] Colin Mark, "Junior Wins Inaugural Robert Caro Award," Horace Mann Record, May 30, 2012.
    [40] Jodi Kantor, "Now, a Chance to Catch Up to His Epochal Vision. At Dinners With Obama, Historians Sensed What He Was Really After: 'A Place in History'," New York Times, November 7, 2012.
    [41] Patrick Beach, "Caro getting more accolades for LBJ epic," Austin American-Statesman, October 27, 2012.
    [42] Printout of photo of Caro signing a book.
    [43] Bill Cunningham, "Red, White And Blue," New York Times, November 11, 2012. Includes a photo of Robert and Ina Caro at the November 8 New York Landmarks Conservancy's Living Landmarks event (2 copies).
    [44-45] Photos of Robert and Ina Caro and friends on an evening cruise in New York Harbor, and one of Caro holding the New York Landmarks Conservancy's Living Landmark award.
    [46] Printout of photo of Caro speaking before Columbia University Graduate School of Journalism, April 24, 2012.
    [47] Printout of thumbnail images of Caro from RobertCaro.com, April 12, 2012.
    [48] Printout of a photo of Caro posed in his office.
    [49] Michael Schaub, "'Power': Robert Caro's Life of Johnson Hits the '60s," www.npr.org, May 2, 2012.
    [50-51] "The 10 Best Books of 2012," New York Times Book Review, December 9, 2012.
    [52-53] "The Power Writer: A Q&A with Historian Robert Caro," City & State, vol. 1, no. 22 (October 22, 2012).
    [54] Whet Moser, "Northwestern Economist: Don't Expect Any More Economic Growth In Your Lifetime," www.chicagomag.com, October 22, 2012.
    [55] Printout of a Dan Rose photo of Caro seated alone in a dining room (see also page 63).
    [56] "Page turners," The Economist, December 8, 2012.
    [57] Printout of a photo of Caro in the U.S. Senate Chamber(?).
    [58] Jennifer Schuessler, "Caro's Book Tops Historians' Poll, With a Surprising No. 2," New York Times, December 13, 2012.
    [59] Jennifer Schuessler, "Caro on Johnson Tops Historian's Poll, but Seward Book Is Close Behind," www.nytimes.com, December 12, 2012.
    [60] "Google Alert – robert caro," December 14, 2012.
    [61] "The Culture" (list of 10 great nonfiction titles, with "Passage of Power" at no. 2), TIME, December 24, 2012.
    [62] Email from Katherine Hourigan, December 17, 2012.
    [63] Dan Rose photo of Caro seated alone in a dining room (see also page 55).
    [64] Email from Katherine Hourigan, December 20, 2012.
    [65-66] "Twelve Months of Reading. We asked 50 of our friends to tell us what books they enjoyed in 2012... ," Wall Street Journal, December 15-16, 2012.
    [67] Janet Maslin, "A Pleasure to Read (And Even Reread)," New York Times, December 21, 2012.
    [68a] Publicity tour schedule for Ina Caro's book "Paris to the Past," July 2011.
    [68b] Email from Robert Weil regarding paperback printing of Ina Caro's book "Paris to the Past," May 17, 2012.
    [69] Email from Katherine Hourigan, May 16, 2012.
    [70] Email from Katherine Hourigan, May 17, 2012.
    [71] Richard Lambert, "Tragedy and triumph. A magisterial biography charts LBJ's progress through the Kennedy years," www.ft.com, May 19, 2012.
    [72] Letter from Francesca Stanfill in praise of Ina Caro's book "Paris to the Past," January 1, 2012.
    [73] Printout of an invitation to a luncheon celebrating the first annual Robert Caro Prize for Literary Excellence in the Writing of History, Horace Mann School, May 29, 2012.
    [74a] Chris McGreal, "Robert Caro: a life with LBJ and the pursuit of power," thelonggoodread.com, June 11, 2012 (incomplete?).
    [74b] Excerpt from "Passage of Power," 2012.
    [75] Copy of a Horace Mann class photo from a school publication.
    [76-77] Michiko Kakutani, "A Nation's Best and Worst, Forged in a Crucible," New York Times, April 30, 2012.
    [78-79] Advertisement for "Passage of Power," New York Times Book Review, May 20, 2012.
    [80] Bill Cunningham, "Red, White And Blue," New York Times, November 11, 2012. Includes a photo of Robert and Ina Caro at the November 8 New York Landmarks Conservancy's Living Landmarks event.
    [inside back cover] Thank-you letter from the Horace Mann students in Barry Bienstock's history seminar who visited Caro's office on April 16, 2012 (see pages 24-27).
    [inside back cover] Copy of a Horace Mann class photo from a school publication.
    [inside back cover] Michiko Kakutani, "A Nation's Best and Worst, Forged in a Crucible," New York Times, April 30, 2012 (2 copies).
    [inside back cover] New York Times Book Review, May 6, 2012 (incomplete copy).
    [inside back cover] New York Times Book Review, May 20, 2012 (3 incomplete copies).
  - Scrapbook [29], "2019-Working", 1961, 1964-1965, 2005, 2010, 2019–2021 (Box [XI-23])
    Cover embossed "2019-Working." Contains mostly reviews and publicity of Working: Researching, Interviewing, Writing, and the acquisition of Caro's papers by the New-York Historical Society.
    [01] Scott Detrow, "In 'Working,' Writer Robert Caro Explains His Process—And What Drives Him," www.npr.org, April 8, 2019.
    [02-03] Robert A. Caro, "Turn Every Page," The New Yorker, January 28, 2019.
    [04-05] Harold Evans, "Biography as Obsession," New York Times Book Review, April 21, 2019.
    [06] Photo of Caro and quote from an unidentified publication (New York Times Magazine?).
    [07] Chris Kornelis, "Why LBJ Biographer Robert Caro Has Written Thousands of Pages by Hand," Wall Street Journal, April 9, 2019.
    [08] Email from Deirdre David, Biographers International Organization, October 11, 2019.
    [09] Publicity tour schedule for "Working," April 9, 2019.
    [10] Fred Volkmer, "Book Review: Robert Caro's 'Working'," 27east.com, September 17, 2019.
    [11] Rachel Cooke, "Interview | Robert Caro: 'The more facts you collect, the closer you come to the truth'," www.theguardian.com, April 21, 2019.
    [12] John Mariani, "Mario's in the Bronx Has Had a Century to Get Everything Right" (restaurant review), Forbes, undated.
    [13] Ruth Scurr, "Truth takes time. The investigative method of a great biographer and writer," Times Literary Supplement, April 26, 2019.
    [14a] Photo of Robert and Ina Caro posed before the "Robert A. Caro '53 History Classroom," Horace Mann School Annual Report of Donors, 2018-2019.
    [14b] "Author of the week: Robert Caro," The Week, April 19, 2019.
    [14c] Guest list for [Vartan] "Gregorian party 4/25/19."
    [15] Jennifer Szalai, "Robert Caro's Path To Literary Power," New York Times, April 11, 2019.
    [16] Stephen Loosley, "The story behind Robert Caro's epic biography of LBJ,' Financial Review, September 18, 2019.
    [17] "Typewriter Repairman Writes 3,000-Page Book, Wins Pulitzer! Historian Robert Caro has 11 identical typewriters. To finish his life's work, he may need more," Popular Mechanics, May 2019.
    [18a] Flier for "Robert Caro on Robert Caro In Conversation with Kai Bird" at the Graduate Center, City University of New York, October 15, 2019.
    [18b] Ben Joravsky, "Mayor Rahm v. Robert Caro," www.chicagoreader.com, May 3, 2019.
    [18c] "Poets cornered," Times Literary Supplement, October 4, 2019.
    [19] Email from Deirdre David, Biographers International Organization, October 11, 2019.
    [20] "By the Book: Adam Hochshild," New York Times Book Review, March 12, 2020.
    [21] Letter from Margaret Engel, January 31, 2020.
    [23] Two postcards from Robert and Ina Caro addressed to Joel Conarroe, one from France (postmarked May 25, 1990), the other from Texas (postmarked March 7, 2005).
    [25] William Feigelman, "Robert Caro's Legacy," letter to The New Yorker, February 11, 2019.
    [26] Robert A. Caro, "Turn Every Page," The New Yorker, January 28, 2019.
    [27] Reproduction of two pages of Caro's typed outline or draft, used in the book "Turn Every Page," inscribed "My beloved Ina— These are the endpapers, the inside back cover, of the book. The material on them was gotten by you. Robert A. Caro."
    [28] Review of "Working: Research, Interviewing, Writing," word-view-officeapps.live.com, February 13, 2019.
    [29] Mention of Shana Caro in chapter 11, "Parental Care," of the Dustin R. Rubenstein and John Alcock textbook "Animal Behavior," eleventh edition.
    [30] Jeffrey A. Trachtenberg, "Robert Caro Has Chronicled LBJ for Decades. Fans Fret He'll Never Finish," Wall Street Journal, February 23-24, 2019.
    [31] Jeffrey A. Trachtenberg, "'Hurry Up Please!' Fans of Robert Caro, 83, Fear He'll Never Finish His Life of LBJ," www.wsj.com, February 22, 2019.
    [32-33] John Gans, "Obama Makes It Harder to See the Arc of History Bend," POLITICO Magazine, www.politico.com, February 25, 2019.
    [34] Chris McGreal, "Robert Caro: a life with LBJ and the pursuit of power," The Guardian, June 9, 2012 (incomplete).
    [35] Fred Bernstein, "In An Explosive Biography, Robert Caro Portrays L.B.J.'s Path to Power as the Low Road," People, January 17, 1983 (incomplete); includes a photo captioned "LBJ cousin Ava Cox, 79, shows the Caros a well behind the Texas homestead granddaddy Sam Ealy Johnson built in 1858."
    [36] Blank except for note: "WOW!!!."
    [37] Advertisement for "Robert Caro Talks Power & Process" for Times Talks, New York Times Book Review, March 10, 2019.
    [38] Jessica Ferri, "Dig, Dig, Dig. Robert Caro Talks Writing and Research: 'Turn Every Page'," thedailybeast.com, March 30, 2019.
    [39] Publicity tour schedule for "Working," [March?], 2019.
    [40-41] [blank]
    [42a] "Various Reviews from Great Britain | Robert Caro," printed from caro.dev.us.randomhouse.com, April 4, 2012.
    [42b] John Rentoul, review of "Passage of Power," www.independent.co.uk, August 27, 2012.
    [43] An appreciation of Caro torn from an unidentified publication (incomplete).
    [44] [blank]
    [45-47] Dan Barry, "A Peek at Robert Caro's Yellowed Files," New York Times, January 9, 2021.
    [49] "Reader Comments," New York Times, January 17, 2021.
    [50-53] Harold Evans, "Robert A. Caro, Private Eye," New York Times, April 16, 2019.
    [54] Joel Conarroe, "The Power Broker," letter to the editor, New York Times, October 28, 2010.
    [55] David Marchese, "Robert Caro on the means and ends of power," New York Times, April 1, 2019.
    [56-61] [blank]
    [62-64] David Marchese, "Robert A. Caro on means and ends," Talk, New York Times Magazine, April 7, 2019.
    [65] William Feigelman, "Robert Caro's Legacy," letter to The New Yorker, February 11, 2019.
    [66] Richard Lambert, "How to get to the root of political power," Financial Times, April 13-14, 2019.
    [67] "Best books... chosen by Colm Tóibín," The Week, December 20, 2019.
    [68] Jennifer Schuessler, "Robert Caro's Papers Find a Home," New York Times, January 8, 2020.
    [69-70] Photos of Caro being interviewed at the New-York Historical Society on publication of "Working.'
    [71] Photo of Caro with Conan O'Brien.
    [72] Jacket blurbs for "Path to Power," "Means of Ascent," and "Master of the Senate."
    [73] Photos of Robert and Ina Caro.
    [74-87] [blank]
    [88] John Leland, "The Dutch Prime Minister Is a Big Fan of Robert Caro," New York Times, May 13, 2016.
    [inside back cover] Robert A. Caro, "He Uses Hands, Heart to Get Education," Newsday, May 24, 1961 (inside envelope from America-Israel Cultural Foundation mailed to Picture Editor, Newsday, received March 20, 1964).
    [inside back cover] Dan Barry, "A Peek at Robert Caro's Yellowed Files," New York Times, January 9, 2021 (two copies folded inside main section of the newspaper).
    [inside back cover] Envelope marked "Mr. Robert Caro" and "Newsday" containing (1) newspaper articles by and about Caro, circa 1964-1965; (2) photo of Caro receiving Lincoln Plaquette from G. Hanlon, director of promotion and research, WGN Inc., Chicago, at the Illinois Pavilion, New York World's Fair; (3) photo of Caro receiving an award (the words "New York Herald Tribune" are visible at bottom of plaque); (4) photos of Caro
    [inside back cover] Photo of queue of visitors waiting to enter the New York Public Library, presumably for the opening of the exhibition "You Say You Want a Revolution: Remembering the 60s," January 19-September 1, 2018.
- Series XII. Objects